articlesnetwork.com 2007-12-14

# Privacy Policy for ArticlesNetwork.com

**ARTICLESNETWORK.COM & ASSOCIATES & OWNERS  
**   

Note from site owner:  Primarily our privacy policy is very simple.  I despise spam and everything it destroys on the internet.  I simply would not subject you to any more of it than is already polluting our wonderful net already.  I respect you as a fellow human being as well as your rights to sign up for whatever you want, not something that you don't want. When you get on any list that belongs to me, you can be assured that there isn't enough money on the planet to coerce me into selling your information to be abused.  There's already too doggone much of that cr*p going on as it is.  Morals down the tube.  (Oh... this sounds like an article.)  Mainly, your privacy is safe, respected and will NOT be shared unless you break the law.  Succinct and straightforward.  So... enjoy the site, and if you want to read the in-depth version, it's below:

## ****Our PRIVACY POLICY****

Welcome to ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owner(s) (the "Site").

We understand that privacy online is important to users of our Site, especially when conducting business.   
This statement governs our privacy policies with respect to those users of the Site ("Visitors") who visit without   
transacting business and Visitors who register to transact business on the Site and make use of the various services offered by ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners (collectively, "Services") ("Authorized Customers").

**"Personally Identifiable Information"** refers to any information that identifies or can be used to identify, contact, or locate the person to whom such information pertains, including, but not limited to, name, address, phone number, fax number, email address, financial profiles, social security number, and credit card information. Personally Identifiable Information does not include information that is collected anonymously (that is, without identification of the individual user)   
or demographic information not connected to an identified individual.

**What Personally Identifiable Information is collected?** We may collect basic user profile information from all of our Visitors. We collect the following additional information from our Authorized Customers: the names, addresses, phone numbers and email addresses of Authorized Customers, the nature and size of the business, and the nature and size of the advertising inventory that the Authorized Customer intends to purchase or sell.

**What organizations are collecting the information?  
 **  
In addition to our direct collection of information, our third party service vendors (such as credit card companies, clearinghouses and banks) who may provide such services as credit, insurance, and escrow services may collect this information from our Visitors and Authorized Customers. We do not control how these third parties use such information, but we do ask them to disclose how they use personal information provided to them from Visitors and Authorized Customers. Some of these third parties may be intermediaries that act solely as links in the distribution chain, and do not store, retain, or use the information given to them.

**How does the Site use Personally Identifiable Information?** We use Personally Identifiable Information to customize the Site, to make appropriate service offerings, and to fulfill buying and selling requests on the Site. We may email Visitors and Authorized Customers about research or purchase and selling opportunities on the Site or information related to the subject matter of the Site. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to contact Visitors and Authorized Customers in response to specific inquiries, or to provide requested information. 

**With whom may the information may be shared?** Personally Identifiable Information about Authorized Customers may be shared with other Authorized Customers who wish to evaluate potential transactions with other Authorized Customers. We may share aggregated information about our Visitors, including the demographics of our Visitors and Authorized Customers, with our affiliated agencies and third party vendors. We also offer the opportunity to "opt out" of receiving information or being contacted by us or by any agency acting on our behalf. 

**How is Personally Identifiable Information stored?**

Personally Identifiable Information collected by ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners is securely stored and is not accessible to third parties or employees of ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners except for use as indicated above. 

**What choices are available to Visitors regarding collection, use and distribution of the information?**  
Visitors and Authorized Customers may opt out of receiving unsolicited information from or being contacted by us and/or our vendors and affiliated agencies by responding to emails as instructed, or by contacting us at [admin [[at]] ArticlesNetwork.com ](mailto:admin%20%5B%5Bat%5D%5D%20ArticlesNetwork.com)

**Are Cookies Used on the Site?** Cookies are used for a variety of reasons. We use Cookies to obtain information about the preferences of our Visitors and the services they select. We also use Cookies for security purposes to protect our Authorized Customers. For example, if an Authorized Customer is logged on and the site is unused for more than 10 minutes, we will automatically log the Authorized Customer off.

**How does ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners use login information?  
 **  
ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners uses login information, including, but not limited to, IP addresses, ISPs, and browser types, to analyze trends, administer the Site, track a user's movement and use, and gather broad demographic information.

**What partners or service providers have access to Personally Identifiable Information from Visitors and/or Authorized Customers on the Site?** ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners has entered into and will continue to enter into partnerships and other affiliations with a number of vendors.  Such vendors may have access to certain Personally Identifiable Information on a need to know basis for evaluating Authorized Customers for service eligibility.   Our privacy policy does not cover their collection or use of this information.   
  
Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to comply with law. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information in order to comply with a court order or subpoena or a request from a law enforcement agency to release information. We will also disclose Personally Identifiable Information when reasonably necessary to protect the safety of our Visitors and Authorized Customers. 

**How does the Site keep Personally Identifiable Information secure?** All of our employees are familiar with our security policy and practices. The Personally Identifiable Information of our Visitors and Authorized Customers is only accessible to a limited number of qualified employees who are given a password in order to gain access to the information. We audit our security systems and processes on a regular basis. Sensitive information, such as credit card numbers or social security numbers, is protected by encryption protocols, in place to protect information sent over the Internet. While we take commercially reasonable measures to maintain a secure site, electronic communications and databases are subject to errors, tampering and break-ins, and we cannot guarantee or warrant that such events will not take place and we will not be liable to Visitors or Authorized Customers for any such occurrences. 

**How can Visitors correct any inaccuracies in Personally Identifiable Information?** Visitors and Authorized Customers may contact us to update Personally Identifiable Information about them or to correct any inaccuracies by emailing us at [admin [[at]] ArticlesNetwork.com ](mailto:admin%20%5B%5Bat%5D%5D%20ArticlesNetwork.com)

**Can a Visitor delete or deactivate Personally Identifiable Information collected by the Site?** We provide Visitors and Authorized Customers with a mechanism to delete/deactivate Personally Identifiable Information from the Site's database by contacting [admin [[at]] ArticlesNetwork.com ](mailto:admin%20%5B%5Bat%5D%5D%20ArticlesNetwork.com). However, because of backups and records of deletions, it may be impossible to delete a Visitor's entry without retaining some residual information. An individual who requests to have Personally Identifiable Information deactivated will have this information functionally deleted, and we will not sell, transfer, or use Personally Identifiable Information relating to that individual in any way moving forward. 

**What happens if the Privacy Policy Changes?** We will let our Visitors and Authorized Customers know about changes to our privacy policy by posting such changes on the Site. However, if we are changing our privacy policy in a manner that might cause disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information that a Visitor or Authorized Customer has previously requested not be disclosed, we will contact such Visitor or Authorized Customer to allow such Visitor or Authorized Customer to prevent such disclosure. 

**PLEASE NOTE:**

This Site is not directed at children. Visitors and Authorized Customers are required to be eighteen years or older.  Thank you for understanding, this grandmother respects child protection laws as much as anyone could.  Our children are precious and they need all our watchfulness and protective love they can get.

**Regarding Links:** This web site contains links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are moving to another web site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policies may differ from ours. 

© 2005 **ArticlesNetwork.com & Associates & Owners** , All rights reserved.  

Unauthorized duplication or publication of any materials from this Site is expressly prohibited.  See our specific guidelines for using the intellectual property on this website.  Look under Submission Guidelines in the right-hand column for details.    

Get your own free Privacy Policy [here](http://www.prioritydigital.com/)!   We express our thanks to the great folks at Priority Digital for sharing their resources so freely with webmasters who need it.  Thank you.  

* * *

Further Disclaimer from TOS page:  You agree to not hold ArticlesNetwork.com or its owners liable for the accuracy of any article on this or any other site controlled by Donna Maher &/or Associates, and you acknowledge that  ArticlesNetwork.com is simply a center of mutual interest and publishing activity where authors and publishers may meet. 

Intellectual Property Note:

If you suspect someone of stealing your original work, please contact us with details and we will remove the article in question immediately.  ArticlesNetwork.com implicitly does not endorse any author, website, or product mentioned in any articles not written specifically by the ArticlesNetwork.com team or its members. 

All articles published by ArticlesNetwork.com are not intended to be used for legal, medical, or any other type of advice. All articles are for informational purposes only and ArticlesNetwork.com nor it's owners or authors are responsible for any ramifications by article readers who do not read or heed this TOS.

   [Lastly, although in an ideal world this shouldn't be necessary, but unfortunately is:  This is a clean, law-abiding, family-oriented website and we will not hesitate to remove SPAM, p*o*r*n, and any illegal-type or other malevolent articles or material as well as be obliged to report the offender to the appropriate authorities wherever applicable.]  

* * *
